## SAMUEL L. RANDALL

#### samrandall@alumni.stanford.edu

I help teams use data, software and AI to solve technical and business challenges. I have expertise building automated pipelines for data analysis, training and integrating ML models into software, and using mathematical and computational techniques to solve hard problems. I also have experience creating business strategy and can advise business executives on technical matters.

### **Education**

**Stanford University**, MS. Computational & Mathematical Engineering DGSAC Exceptional Master's Student Award.

- Computational Geometry course with Dr. Leonidas Guibas.
- Robotics Research in Bohg Lab, Unsupervised Learning Research in Hazy Lab.

**Johns Hopkins University**, BS. Applied Mathematics and Public Health. Minor in Computer Science and Environmental Science.

# **Experience**

#### BlueLightAI, Principal Applied Scientist

January 2023 — Present

- Developed software algorithm (based in topological data analysis) to automatically identify systemic error patterns in ML models, resulting in improved operational efficiency for our team.
- Tested this algorithm on many fine-tuned Llama models, fine-tuned BERT classification models, fine-tuned ResNet, tabular ML models, exhibiting their time-saving success across many models.
- Planned & organized PoVs and technical deliverables in GTM, aligning the team around technical tasks that create value.

#### Athena Security, iOS Engineer

2020 - 2022

- Integration of sensors and ML model into MVP fever detection iOS app in 6 weeks.
- Engaged in rapid feedback loop with prospects & customers to engineer the product to suit needs, making necessary third-party integrations and satisfying new feature requests.

#### PHICOR, Research Analyst

2017 - 2020

- Scripted the execution & analysis of simulation runs; automating a labor-intensive process.
- Streamlined labor-intensive download / organization process of large (>1500 files) dataset.

# **Volunteer & Continuing Education**

California Search & Rescue, Duty Officer, General Member

2022 — Present

• I receive the call from emergency service, dispatch the team & coordinate logistics.

Climate Change Solution-Oriented Reading Group, Cofounder	2023 — Present
Stanford University, Sighted Running Guide for Visually Impaired Students	2022 - 2023
Large Language Model (LLM) Reading Group, General Member	2023 - 2024

# **STEM Teaching & Tutoring Experience**

Ordinary Differential Equations, Course Assistant	2022
Software Development for Engineers and Scientists, Course Assistant	2021
Juni Learning, Computer Science Tutor for children aged 5-18	2019 - 2020

## **Skills**

SWE: Python, Java, Javascript, Swift, C/C++, PyTorch, git, Unix, CUDA, Data Structures, Algorithms.

Data: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision (CV), NLP, scikit-learn, LLMs.

Math: Graph Theory, Discrete Mathematics, Applied Topology, Computational Geometry, Convex Optimization.